Daniel Cucinotta

Fair Lawn, NJ

cucinotta.daniel024@gmail.com

973-910-1715







SUMMARY OF QUALIFICATIONS

Data Specialist / Analyst for various types of systems as well as Full-Stack Web Developer with more than 4 years of educational experience in designing, implementing, and managing secure databases, including mapping / configuring networks. Ambitious with focus and dexterity to perform a vast range of tasks apropos data scraping operations for producing custom datasets as well as clean, standardize, merge, and explore data. Additionally, the aptitude to execute statistical functions, generate various types of machine learning models as well as descriptive analytics models to produce a variety of visualizations and comprehensive reports. Adept, versatile, and resourceful with numerous programming languages, software, and platforms for an extensive array of IT roles including building aesthetically appealing responsive websites with HTML, JavaScript, and CSS. Possess excellent written / verbal communication and leadership skills as well as the capacity to conduct work independently and / or collaboratively.

EDUCATION

Western Governors University

Durham, NC

Bachelor of Science: Data Management / Data Analytics

April 2024

- GPA: 3.0 / 3.0
- Data science / analytics procedures and tools, encompassing various combinations of languages as well as formats / methods to produce statistical graphics using PostgreSQL, Jupyter Notebook (Python and R), Excel, Power BI, Tableau, and MATLAB.
- Data / information management and governance.
- Project management and IT leadership roles as well as IT business concepts / practices.

Pitt Community College

Winterville, NC

Associate in Applied Science: Computer Programming and Development

June 2018 - December 2021

Associate in Arts

June 2018 - December 2021

- GPA: 4.0 / 4.0 (cumulative dual degree)
- Programming with SQL, Python, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, C++, and JAVA.
- Design, implement, deploy databases, including networks and security with Linux, CISCO, and Oracle, as well as NoSQL with the interchangeability of stack components such as MongoDB, Express, Angular, and Node.
- Working with virtual environments and containers as well as connectivity and deployment

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Programming Languages: <u>SQL</u>, <u>Python</u>, <u>R</u>, JavaScript / JSON / jQuery / Express / Angular / node, <u>C++</u>, <u>Java</u>,
 HTML5, and CSS / SCSS.
- Operating Systems: Linux (Bash) And Windows (PowerShell).
- Software: pgAdmin4, SQL Server (SSMS), MS Office, Adobe CS5, <u>Tableau</u>, Power BI, Anaconda (Pandas and Tidyverse), MATLAB, Knime, and Wireshark.

- Databases: Excel, PostgreSQL, MS SQL, MySQL, and NoSQL (MongoDB).
- Platforms: Git/GitHub/Github.io, Google APIs, Docker, and Heroku.
- IDEs: VSCode, Jupyter, PyCharm, R Studio, WebStorm, Dreamweaver, Code::Blocks, and SQL Developer.
- Data Scraping: Python (Beautiful Soup), and R (rvest).

PROJECT EXPERIENCE

Data Analyst

Bachelor's Capstone April 2024

Examined World Data Analyst Jobs and Salaries 2020 – 2023 by merging, cleaning, and standardizing 5 datasets
as well as produced an illustrated presentation of several dashboards in a story with Tableau. A comprehensive
report outlining the datasets, processes, and analyses was assembled to convey the information gleaned from the
visual models as well as the statistical significance and fit of testing the data models.

Website Developer

Portfolio 👨 May 2024

 Designed as well as deployed a responsive website with the utilization of JavaScript / JSON / jQuery, CSS / SCSS, and HTML. A portfolio showcasing projects and accomplishments was developed to demonstrate proficiency as well as the inclusion of a profile section.

Database Designer

<u>Associate's Capstone</u> February 2020

- Design and implementation of a secure RAID RDBMS.
- Fabricated the DFD, ERD, and UML diagrams as well as an online help desk.
- Devised a plan addressing all phases of the Database Life Cycle as well as a backup plan.

ADDITIONAL SKILLS & CERTIFICATIONS

Udacity Online

Data Analyst Nanodegree (U

April 2023 - October 2023

- Culmination of 5 courses outlining universal aspects, strategies, and a range of methods regarding data analytics by means of multiple languages and applications.
- Data analysis as well as practical statistics theories and pertinent use cases.
- Data wrangling as well as statistical and visual modeling.
- Data collection and analysis using R and ggplot.
- Supervised and unsupervised machine learning algorithms, techniques, and approaches.
- Data visualization functions and tools such as matplotlib, seaborn, and Tableau.

CIW

Data Analyst February 2023

 Big Data, containerization concepts / functionality, and CRM software as well as performing operations in R, with Knime, OpenRefine, and Google Cloud.

ITIL4

IT Service Management Certification

December 2022

- Service management, organizational governance, and IT business practices.
- Streamline operational efficiency with system configurations, material flow mapping, value chain, and contracting vendors as well as infrastructure / platform management policies, including incidence response protocols.

CompTIA

Project+ Certificate

November 2022

- The multitude of aspects and levels of project management spanning from concept to customer.
- Project planning guidelines entailing scheduling, resource procurement, roles, and risk management.

CompTIA

Network+ Certificate

September 2022

 Comprehension of the OSI model, routing / switching, and troubleshooting network infrastructure as well as business continuity. Network activity monitoring, as well as identifying performance and availability issues.

CompTIA

A+ Certificate

September 2022

 Attained by passing 2 core skills tests delineating expansive coverage of ubiquitous IT concepts: hardware, networks, infrastructure, mobile devices, virtualization, cloud computing, and troubleshooting.

CISCO

Cybersecurity Essentials Certificate

August 2019

- Employed security controls on networks, servers, and applications with Cisco Packet Tracer.
- Systematically ensuring data confidentiality, integrity, authenticity, and availability as well as policy compliance.

CISCO

Networking Essentials Certificate

August 2019

 Planning, Installing, and troubleshooting networks (wired / wireless) as well as identify and mitigate security threats using Cisco Packet Tracer.

HONORS & INVOLVEMENT

National Society of Leadership and Success

Foundations of Leadership Certificate

06/04/2021

Qualified with persistent, focused dedication to educational endeavors as well as engaged in team discussions.

Phi Theta Kappa 🛔

Winterville, NC

Beta Nu Epsilon Chapter

04/16/2020

Distinctively satisfied requirements, and awarded the WGU Phi Theta Kappa Scholarship for essays submitted.

Gamma Beta Phi

Winterville, NC

Pitt Community College

05/26/2019

Esteemed member by eligibility.